<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to My Site on My thoughts</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to My Site on My thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Transparency: Clarity Without Spilling Secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/create-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/create-transparency/</guid>
      <description>Part 3 of the 13-part series on what behaviours make you trustworthy. Aarav and Abheer tackle the fine line between transparency and confidentiality — with lessons from Ambedkar, Mandela, and Netflix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrate Respect: It Starts with How You Look at People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/demonstrate-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/demonstrate-respect/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of the 13-part series of articles on what behaviours make you trustworthy. Abheer and Aarav explore why respect isn’t just politeness — it is recognition of worth, especially when things go wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk Straight: Say What You Mean</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/talk-straight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/trust-series/talk-straight/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of the 13-part series of articles on what behaviours make you trustworthy. . Aarav and Abheer explore why candor builds trust — and how Feynman and Klopp show us the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feedback With Grace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/feedback-with-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 16:10:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/feedback-with-grace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;turning-feedback-into-fuel-a-practical-framework-for-responding-and-growing&#34;&gt;Turning Feedback into Fuel: A Practical Framework for Responding and Growing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback can be a gift, a challenge, or sometimes—let&amp;rsquo;s be honest—a source of frustration. It can feel uplifting when constructive, disorienting when vague, and demoralizing when unfair. But in every form, feedback presents an opportunity: to understand, to grow, and to lead with maturity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is an attempt to lay out a clear method for anyone—whether you&amp;rsquo;re in a leadership position or early in your career—to effectively receive, question, and act on the provided feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Your Worth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-your-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 16:09:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-is-your-worth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;defining-ones-worth-in-a-professional-context-a-balanced-framework&#34;&gt;Defining One&amp;rsquo;s Worth in a Professional Context: A Balanced Framework&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you define your worth at work? Is it just your output, your impact, or how visible your work is? The answer isn&amp;rsquo;t simple, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. Worth is multi-dimensional and must be evaluated holistically. Drawing inspiration from InfraCloud&amp;rsquo;s career ladder framework, here&amp;rsquo;s a way to look at it more constructively, especially in engineering and leadership roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-core-principle-worth--quantitative-impact--qualitative-value&#34;&gt;The Core Principle: Worth = Quantitative Impact + Qualitative Value&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantitative impact is what’s typically easier to measure: lines of code, bugs resolved, features shipped, planning accuracy, deadlines met. But qualitative value is where the real distinction lies—decisiveness in ambiguity, operating in constrained environments, building trust, driving alignment, and creating clarity where none exists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leverage as Currency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leverage-as-currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 21:19:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leverage-as-currency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leverage-the-real-currency-in-organizations&#34;&gt;Leverage: The Real Currency in Organizations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my thought experiment in writing an article or a short post in a conversational manner. I loved the book &amp;ldquo;The courage to be disliked&amp;rdquo;, and i have tried to mimic the style in presenting an argument and a counter argument making it a lot more personable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A conversation between Aarav and Abheer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a Sunday afternoon. Aarav and Abheer are seated at a quiet coffee shop. They have been talking about work, influence, and what really moves the needle within organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phantom Jams in Orgs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phantom-jams-in-orgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:28:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phantom-jams-in-orgs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-phantom-jam-in-organizations&#34;&gt;The Phantom Jam in Organizations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently learnt about something called Phantom Jams (this while being part of a traffic jam myself. I am from Bangalore, so thats nothing new for me.)
The fascinating part is that a phantom jam has got nothing to do with a crash. They start with a tap on the brake and the car behind then brakes harder so on and so forth which causes a cascading effect triggering a chain reaction, eventually causing subsequent drivers to slow down and create a jam. This can and mostly happens even in relatively free-flowing traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auth and Authz for a 5 yr old</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eita5-auth-authz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eita5-auth-authz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;authentication-and-authorization-to-a-5yr-old&#34;&gt;Authentication and Authorization to a 5yr old&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this article is to help understand concepts by breaking them down and drawing parallels in the world to give the reader a model to understand them. Try to explain them as if you were explaining it to a 5 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an attempt to explain Authorization and Authentication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets take a visit to a theme park as an example. You and your 5 year old visit a theme park say, Disney world or Universal studios. And there are lots of fun activities within the park such as fun rides, theme based activities etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Great Responsibilities Come Great Rights (and Guardrails)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rights-and-responsibilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 17:40:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rights-and-responsibilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spiderman said, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;with great power comes great responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; I would say &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;with great responsibilities come great rights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And i have seen far too many engineers, team leads, managers, middle management fail because they weren&amp;rsquo;t empowered/enabled to make the decisions for the responsibilities assigned to them. Here is my attempt to provide some thoughts on how do you make it work (what has worked for me)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a social construct we always talk about rights and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular Communication needs Logging Levels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-logging-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:19:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-logging-levels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;debugging-communication-why-regular-communication-needs-logging-levels&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debugging Communication: Why Regular Communication needs Logging Levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over my career span, I have seen many engineers miss out on well-deserved recognition. And this is not because their work wasn’t great, but because they didn’t represent it appropriately.
Whether it’s providing status updates or showcasing completed work, how you communicate matters just as much as what you communicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any business, an engineer (or any professional, really) interacts with at least three to four different personas:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes for a 5-Year-Old: The Hotel Analogy (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eita5-k8s-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 21:40:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eita5-k8s-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kubernetes-for-a-5-year-old-the-hotel-analogy-part-1&#34;&gt;Kubernetes for a 5-Year-Old: The Hotel Analogy (Part 1)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is again an article drawing parallels from the real world for explaining a distributed system such as kubernetes (k8s) to a 5 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets imagine you are traveling to a big, luxurious hotel for a vacation. The hotel is well-organized, with different rooms, amenities, and staff members ensuring guests have a smooth stay. Now, let’s take this hotel experience and compare it to a distributed platform such as &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Excellence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-paradox-of-excellence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 13:52:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-paradox-of-excellence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📋 Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article and the accompanying questionnaire aims to measure two critical organizational phenomena that most growing companies inevitably encounter. As organizations scale, sustaining a culture that not only values excellence but also effectively identifies and rewards it becomes essential. However, as excellence becomes widespread, a paradox emerges; one that can either dilute its value or end up overburdening excellent performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining excellence before we move further. It is not limited by these traits but on a broad stroke anybody who executes and exhibits these below traits might be considered an excellent performer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-journey&#34;&gt;My Journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Hrishi, a computer science graduate with 20+ years in the software industry. I thrive on challenges and stepping outside my comfort zone—most recently, helping a startup scale from a handful of engineers to over 200 employees. My contributions have spanned engineering, hiring, sales, presales, finance, and now business operations. I’m always looking for new problems to solve. I love mentoring, sharing knowledge, and debating strong opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-years--education&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Years &amp;amp; Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born into a middle-income family in Thane, Maharashtra. I wasn’t a standout student in school or college—academic scores never really interested me. What did? Tinkering. I spent my time setting up house wiring with my dad, fixing appliances, opening up VCRs, mixers, and tape recorders just to put them back together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
